<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quickie on Chris&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.nadeau.tv/tags/quickie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quickie on Chris&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 16:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nadeau.tv/tags/quickie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quickie: Color console output with parallel command</title>
      <link>https://www.nadeau.tv/post/color-console-output-parallel-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nadeau.tv/post/color-console-output-parallel-command/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got a Lerna monorepos with a few microservices. I needed to run the dev version a few of these microservices so I decided to use parallel to run them all at the same time in my terminal:
parallel --tagstring &amp;#39;{/}&amp;#39; --linebuffer &amp;#39;cd {} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; npm run dev&amp;#39; ::: packages/service-a packages/service-b packages/service-c This worked, but I noticed that the color output was stripped when doing this. This is really annoying. The color really helps during development to spot errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickie: Prevent Mac apps from quitting when last window is closed</title>
      <link>https://www.nadeau.tv/post/quickie-prevent-osx-from-closing-when-last-window-is-closed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 10:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nadeau.tv/post/quickie-prevent-osx-from-closing-when-last-window-is-closed/</guid>
      <description>There are a few apps on OSX that quit/terminate once their window is closed. This is typical on Windows of course, but it&amp;rsquo;s a bit random on OSX. Some (most?) apps stay open, and some close. I find it really bloody annoying. I&amp;rsquo;ll quit my apps when I&amp;rsquo;m ready to quit them, thank you very much.
The biggest sore spot with me is 1password which I use dozens of times a day, and every time I CMD+W to close the window (muscle memory!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickie: Quickly rename MySQL database</title>
      <link>https://www.nadeau.tv/post/quickie-quickly-rename-mysql-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 17:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nadeau.tv/post/quickie-quickly-rename-mysql-database/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s no way to rename a MySQL database. Typical advice is to dump/restore the database, but this is obviously very slow if you have a huge database.
I found a solution today. Create your database, then execute this one-line:
mysql -uUSER -pPASS OLD_DB -sNe &#39;SHOW TABLES&#39; | while read t; do mysql -u username -ppassword -sNe &amp;quot;rename table OLD_DB.$t to NEW_DB.$t&amp;quot;; done  Obviously replace the params as necessary.
 Or here&amp;rsquo;s the same as a slightly easier to read bash script:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
